Brendan Kennedy

btkenned@usc.edu

@berendennedy

https://brendankennedy.org

G Google Scholar

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/brendan-kennedy-usc/

https://github.com/BrendanKennedy



I am a 5th year Ph.D. student, studying computer science in the Computational Social Sciences Laboratory (CSSL) with Morteza Dehghani. I research in the area of computational methods and the social sciences, particularly with regard to measurements of natural language.

Education

2016 – present

Ph.D., Computer Science, University of Southern California

Expected Completion: 2022

Research Topic: Explainable NLP and Text Analysis Methods

2012 - 2016

■ B.S. Computer Science, Gonzaga University Magna cum Laude

Minors: Mathematics and Philosophy

Research Publications

Preprints, Under Review & Under Revision

- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Hoover, J., Omrani, A., Graham, J., & Dehghani, M. (2020). Moral concerns are differentially observable in language. PsyArXiv.

 https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/uqmty
- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Yeh, L., Omrani, A., Kim, Y., Coombs Jr., K., Havaldar, S., Portillo-Wightman, G., Gonzalez, E., Hoover, J., Azatian, A., Cardenas, G., Hussain, A., Lara, A., Omary, A., Park, C., Wang, X., Wijaya, C., ... Dehghani, M. (2020). The gab hate corpus: A collection of 27k posts annotated for hate speech. PsyArXiv.

 \textstyle{\mathcal{O}} https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/hqjxn
- Hoover, J., Atari*, M., Mostafazadeh Davani*, A., **Kennedy***, **B.**, Portillo-Wightman, G., Yeh, L., Kogon, D., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Bound in hatred: The role of group-based morality in acts of hate. PsyArXiv.

Journal Articles

- Hoover, J., Portillo-Wightman, G., Yeh, L., Havaldar, S., Davani, A., Lin, Y., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Atari, M., Kamel, Z., Mendlen, M., Moreno, G., Park, C., Chang, T., Chin, J., Leong, C., Leung, J., Mirinjian, A., & Dehghani, M. (2020). Moral foundations twitter corpus: A collection of 35k tweets annotated for moral sentiment. *Social Psychological and Personality Science*.
- Garten, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Hoover, J., Sagae, K., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Incorporating demographic embeddings into language understanding. *Cognitive Science*, 43(1).

 https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12701
- Garten*, J., **Kennedy***, **B.**, Sagae, K., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Measuring the importance of context when modeling language comprehension. *Behavior Research Methods*, 51(2), 480–492.
- 4 Hossain, K., Gao, S., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Galstyan, A., & Natarajan, P. (2018). Forecasting violent events in the middle east and north africa using the hidden markov model and regularized autoregressive models. *Journal of Defense Modeling and Simulation*.

Conference Proceedings

- **Kennedy***, **B.**, Jin*, X., Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Dehghani, M., & Ren, X. (2020). Contextualizing hate speech classifiers with post-hoc explanation, In *Proceedings of the 2020 annual conference of the association for computational linguistics*.
- Mostafazadeh Davani, A., Atari, M., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Havaldar, S., & Dehghani, M. (2020). Hatred is in the eye of the annotator: Hate speech classifiers learn human-like social stereotypes (in press), In *Proceedings of the 42nd annual conference of the cognitive science society (cogsci)*.
- Courtland, M., Davani, A., Reyes, M., Yeh, L., Leung, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Dehghani, M., & Zevin, J. (2019a). Modeling performance differences on cognitive tests using lstms and skip-thought vectors trained on reported media consumption., In *Proceedings of the third workshop on natural language processing and computational social science (nlp+css).*
- Courtland, M., Davani, A., Reyes, M., Yeh, L., Leung, J., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Dehghani, M., & Zevin, J. (2019b). Subtle differences in language experience moderate performance on language-based cognitive tests, In *Proceedings of the 41st annual conference of the cognitive science society, austin, texas. cognitive science society.*
- Davani, A. M., Yeh, L., Atari, M., **Kennedy**, **B.**, Portillo-Wightman, G., Gonzalez, E., Delong, N., Bhatia, R., Mirinjian, A., Ren, X., & Dehghani, M. (2019). Reporting the unreported: Event extraction for analyzing the local representation of hate crimes, In *Proceedings of the 2019 conference on empirical methods in natural language processing and 9th international joint conference on natural language processing (emnlp-ijcai).*
- **Kennedy**, **B.**, Carrazza, M., Rasin, A., Furst, J., & Raicu, D. (2015). Applying association rule mining to semantic data in the lung image database consortium, In *Proceedings 15th IEEE International Conference on Data Mining Workshop, ICDMW 2015*.

Employment History

2019 – present Research Assistant, Department of Psychology, Dornsife College of Letters, Arts and Sciences, University of Southern California.

Teaching Assistant, Computer Science Department, Viterbi School of Engineering, University of Southern California.

2016 – 2017 Research Assistant, Computer Science Department, Viterbi School of Engineering, University of Southern California; Information Sciences Institute (ISI), University of Southern California.

Skills

Programming (Experienced) | Python, R, LaTeX, Markdown

Python libraries | pandas numpy tensorflow keras matplotlib seaborn nltk spacy

R packages | tidyverse stats lme4 MASS

References

Available on Request